Preliminary Guide to the Ralph B. Little Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Ralph B. Little collection
1861-1965
MS 1354
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.25
Autograph collection of Ralph B. Little, containing prints and letters of American presidents and other public figures.
Little, Ralph Bulkley
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Ralph B. Little, 1982.
Conditions Governing Access
The originals are in the security file and researchers are required to use electrostatic copies.
Biographical / Historical
Ralph B. Little, Sr., was born around 1890. He received his veterinarian's degree from the University of Pennsylvania in 1914. In the following decades, he made significant advances in preventative veterinary medicine and died on July 27, 1965. Little's son, of the same name and also a doctor, appears to have inherited his father's collection of letters and autographs of presidents and other important historical figures.
Scope and Contents
Autograph collection of Ralph B. Little, containing prints and letters of American presidents and other public figures.
United States -- Politics and government; Autographs (manuscripts); Presidents
- Inventory
  - Hoover, Herbert [drawing with autograph], undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Taft, William Howard [drawing], undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Taft, William Howard [ALS], 1917 June 27 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Lincoln, Abraham [photographic negative from 1864], 1891 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Lincoln, Abraham [ANS], 1864 November 20 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Anderson, Robert [photograph], 1861 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Anderson, Robert [ALS to "Gentlemen"], 1861 May 2 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Agnew, Spiro T. [photograph with autograph], undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Nixon, Richard [TLS to "Dr. Little"], 1960 June 30 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Harrison, Benjamin [image from publication], undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Harrison, Benjamin [ALS to William Bernard Gilpin], 1894 January 19 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Grant, Ulysses S. [drawing], undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Lincoln, Robert T. [drawing], undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Grant, Ulysses S. [ALS], 1877 February 13 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Harding, Warren G. [drawing], undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Harding, Warren G. [TLS to Howard W. Bible], 1917 August 14 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D. [drawing], undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D. [TLS to "Dr. Little"], 1965 September 18 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D. and Richard Nixon [photograph with both autographs], undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Kennedy, John F. [photograph with ANS to Ralph B. Little], undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Welles, Gideon [photograph], undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Welles, Gideon [ALS to I.A. Dahlgren], 1861 December 27 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Garfield, James A. [drawing], undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Olmsted, Helen M. [TLS to Richard Townsend], 1937 July 16 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Lincoln, Abraham [photograph], undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Lincoln, Abraham [ALS to E.M. Stanton with several signatures including Lincoln], 1863 December 11 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Roosevelt, Theodore [photograph], undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Roosevelt, Theodore [TLS to Curtis Guild], 1897 November 5 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Johnson, Lyndon [TLS to Ralph B. Little], 1959 July 27 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Johnson, Lyndon [photograph with autograph], undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Garfield, James A. [ALS to Jennie Encell], 1880 November 2 (Box 1, Folder 31)